在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime...
看上去飞船有了自己的意识！
It appears the ship now possesses a will of its own.
而且它似乎比我们更擅长破译铁堡计划的数据库
It also seems to be doing a better job of decoding the project Iacon database than we were.
不管用什么手段 夺回战舰的控制权！
Regain control of this vessel by any means necessary.
这或许是我们登舰下载铁堡数据库的唯一机会
This could be our only chance to slip aboard and download the Iacon database.
为什么这艘战舰在飞向曼哈顿？
Why is the warship heading for Manhattan?
铁堡的圣物在很久以前失落到了地球上
The Iacon relics landed on Earth eons ago
远早于城市建立的时间
long before the city was built atop it.
福勒探员 才下载了这么点？
Agent Fowler! That's all that's been downloaded?!
快跑！
Run for it!
快 我们快走！
Come on. Here's our ride!
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
那我们必须尽快行动
Then we must act quickly
因为 威震天会毫不犹豫地夺取那里的超级武器…
for Megatron will not hesitate to obtain the potential doomsday devices which lie at the site of each.
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前得到铁堡的遗产
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do
我们就必须分头行动
we must divide our resources.
但是擎天柱
But Optimus
我们人手本来就不足…
when it comes to numbers, we are already at a grave disadvantage.
在目前情况下 快速应变最为重要
Under the circumstances, swiftness of action is paramount.
这是一场我们输不起的竞赛
This is one race that we absolutely cannot afford to lose.
派出多支小队 同时前往这四个地点
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
威震天陛下 您要的第一处坐标具体发掘方案
Lord Megatron, I have assembled the mining detail
我已经拟订好了
you requested for the first set of coordinates.
上次我和打击成功收回了铁堡的遗产
Breakdown and I enjoyed previous success retrieving Iacon relics.
这次我也会用成功向死去的战友致敬
In memory of my fallen comrade, I intend to do the same again.
这是个任务
This is a mission
不是让你出去飙车兜风
not one of your racing excursions.
少在那儿夸夸其谈！
Stop your preening!
服从军令 立即去执行！
Move quickly and operate with a surgeon's skill!
明白我的意思了吗 击倒？
Do you understand me, Knockout?!
呃…遵命 威震天陛下
Explicitly, lord Megatron.
好吧 鉴于打击不幸牺牲 你势单力薄
Now, since the unfortunate loss of Breakdown has left you rather vulnerable
我再给你一个后援
you will require appropriate support.
您真是…考虑周到
How very... repellant.
情势有变
Here's a twist.
看上去霸天虎似乎从曼哈顿撤出了
It would appear that the Decepticons have retreated from Manhattan.
他们就这么…放弃离开了？
They just... up and left?
看上去更像威震天已经派出部队进入了地下
It is more likely that Megatron has already set course for the second set of coordinates
而他自己赶去第二个坐标处了
having dispatched a unit to this relic's underground location.
不用摧毁那片城区吗？
Without busting up a city block to get to it?
他们走了地铁隧道
They used subway tunnels.
纽约有完善的地铁网络贯穿整个城市地下
New York has a whole network of them running beneath the city.
既然人类并没有受到直接威胁
Since the human population no longer seems to be directly threatened
那么我们仍需保持隐蔽行动
maintaining our disguise will be necessary.
阿尔茜 大黄蜂
Arcee, Bumblebee
你们是去这种人口密集地区的最佳人选
you are the best choices to navigate through such a densely populated area.
擎天柱？纽约有八百多万人口
Optimus, New York has more than 8 million people.
即使在地下活动
The odds of being spotted by at least one of them are pretty high
被发现的可能性也很大
even if they are headed underground.
你说这话什么意思？
Where are you going with this?
他们需要个代理人
You're gonna need a face man.
得有人替他们应付局面
Someone who can speak on their behalf.
一个在他们暴露时可以提供掩护的人
A human who can run interference if their cover gets blown.
我进过地铁站
Well, I've actually been in subway stations.
我就生长在一座大都会城市
I grew up in a major metropolis
而不像某位“从来没离开过内华达贾斯帕”先生
unlike Mr. "I've never been outside Jasper, Nevada".
我可去过塞博特恩
I have been to Cybertron.
塞博特恩没有地铁！
Cybertron doesn't have subways.
是吧？
Does it?
从实战经验来看 福勒探员是最佳人选
Agent Fowler's field experience makes him our best candidate.
可惜他还没从霸天虎战舰的遭遇中恢复过来
If he weren't still recovering for his encounter with the Decepticon warship.
而我们却安然无事！这不是偶然！
Which we survived without incident.
好吧 神子和杰克陪大黄蜂还有阿尔茜前往
Very well. Miko and Jack will accompany Arcee and Bumblebee.
太好了！
Yes!
开始传送
Initiate transport
同时开始定位另外三组坐标
and triangulate coordinates of the other three relics.
早说这儿跟塞博特恩不一样吧
Of course, it's no Cybertron...
好吧代理人 我们怎么进入地下
All right, face, how do we get underground?
这个 显然你们不能指望\N直接通过地铁闸门而不被别人注意到
Well, you can't just jump the turnstiles and hope no one notices.
看这边！工地！
Check it out! Construction.
大城市总少不了这个
A fact of life in the big city.
别动 大黄蜂！
Bumblebee, don't move!
输电轨
The third rail.
它是给地铁输送电能的
It carries electricity to power the subway trains.
只要碰一下 噗兹 烧焦你
One touch and zap! You're fried.
他一定是从什么电视节目上学到的这些
He must have learned about that on TV or something.
我们能再快点吗？
Could we please pick up the pace?
这里的湿气会侵蚀我的底盘的
The humidity down here is threatening to corrode my undercarriage.
能别老哼哼 行吗？
Must you hover?!
我们接近了吗？
Are we getting any closer?
准确定位坐标不难
Triangulating the coordinates is one thing...
难的是在这个迷宫里找到通路
but figuring out how to reach them through this maze is another.
钻孔声
Drilling.
是从这边传来的！
It's coming from this way!
神子！
Miko!
神子 你怎么…？
Miko, what is your...
在那边别动！
Hold it right there!
- 见鬼！\N- 见鬼！
- Scrap.\N- Scrap.
你们两个小鬼在这下面做什么？
What are you kids doing down here?
我们是跟学校来郊游的
We're... on a field trip... with our school.
但是我们走丢了
But we got lost.
噢 是吗？
Oh, really?
我跟他说过 我们应该跟上同伴
I told him we should stay with our group
但是“伦纳德”坚持要去找化石
but Leonard here insisted we search for fossils.
我的错
My bad.
我想回家…
I want to go home.
…你能帮我们吗 您是…
Can you help us, mister...
沃莫 叫我沃格也行
Vogel. But you can call me Vogel.
那么 有没有乘坐过清洁工火车？
So, ever ride a sweeper train?
掩护
Face.
这一段是三十年代建造的
And this section was added in the '30s
当时公共工程的一部分
as part of a public-works project.
真…漂亮…
Fascinating.
这些老隧道也有阴暗的一面
But these old tunnels have a dark side, too.
据说有怪异的生物潜伏在这里：
Strange creatures have been said to lurk down here.
巨蟒 白色短吻鳄 甚至还有鼹鼠人
Giant snakes, albino alligators, even mole men.
那不过是些流浪汉无家可归
Well, but those are just people who live down here
才住在这下面 不是吗？
because they have no place else to go, right?
那不过是媒体宣传的
That's what the media wants you to believe.
但要我说 他们来自外太空
But I say, they're from outer space.
我告诉你们
I'm telling you
这些都不是51区干的
Area 51's got nothing on this place.
外星人在这下面呢！
The aliens are down here
他们在组建军队
building up their army
说不定抓了人类做苦役
plotting to use us humans as slave labor.
外星人？哈哈哈 但愿他知道…
Aliens, huh? Hahaha... If he only knew.
我收到一个定位信号
I'm picking up a locator beacon.
虎子们已经挖出了圣物
The 'Cons have unearthed the relic.
快拿给我看看
Well? Let me see it already!
准备交火
Lock and load.
还愣着干什么！
Attack, already!
我去抢圣物
I'll get the relic!
你的脸蛋很漂亮
You have lovely features
正适合来搞一个\N我称之为“呲牙裂嘴”的痛苦小实验
perfect for a painful little procedure I call  the "nip and tuck".
回旋踢！
Dodge and kick.
电倒你！
Shock and drop.
这边！
This way.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?
神子 让我们好好想想
Miko, let's think this through.
为什么？你觉得我不知道自己在做什么？
Why? 'Cause you think I don't know what I'm doing?
“我是杰克 擎天柱派我去塞博特恩\N所以我肯定什么都懂！”
"I'm Jack! Optimus picked me to go to Cybertron, so I must know everything!"
好了神子 你真这么想？
Okay, Miko, seriously...
如果那就是你的烦心事 那之前为什么不说？
if that's what's bugging you, then why didn't you say something before?
我在努力克制
I've been holding it in.
你还会克制？
Since when do you hold anything in?
你看 这不是说你就没有贡献
Look, it's not like you don't contribute.
就在昨天\N你还帮忙击落了一艘发了神经的霸天虎飞船！
Just yesterday, you helped take down a psychotic Decepticon warship.
这不是在竞赛！
This isn't a competition!
迷路了 哈？
Lost, huh?
你们俩得跟纽约交通管理部门解释清楚！
You two are gonna have to explain yourselves to the New York transit authority.
我想我们应该说出真相
I think we should tell him the truth.
好吧
Right.
事实上…我们弄丢了我们的狗
The truth is... we lost our dog.
你在白费口舌！
You're wasting your breath.
真正的真相！
The real truth.
我们需要阻止外星人
We're trying to prevent aliens
不能让他们挖出一种远古的强力武器 否则我们的星球会被毁灭！
from digging up a powerful ancient relic so they can't use it to destroy our planet.
我就觉得今天早些时候我听到了奇怪的声音
I swore I heard something weird and high-pitched earlier today...
在五号道挖掘的那些肯定不是施工队！
something that wasn't the crew drilling over on track 5.
现在 让我们来看看你到底是个啥 有啥作用
Now, shall we see precisely what you are and what you do?
除了进行活体试验
And what better way to learn your power
还有什么更好的方法呢？
than to conduct an on-site experiment?
鼹鼠人！金属的！
Mole men! Metal ones!
事实上 是霸天虎
Actually, Decepticons.
他们抓住了阿尔茜和大黄蜂！
And they have Arcee and Bumblebee.
沃格 这玩意儿还能开得更快吗？
Vogel, this thing have another gear?
当然能！
Abso-Freakin'-Lutely!
嘿！小心我的喷漆！
Hey! Watch the finish!
我也不喜欢逃跑 不过我得去赶火车了！
Hate to run, but I just missed my train.
去追圣物 我去带回杰克和神子！
Follow the relic. I'll grab Jack and Miko.
不太妙！一定是刹车线坏了！
Not good. Brake line must have been torched.
没法刹车？
We can't stop?
没关系
No big deal.
这条轨道有几英里长 不是吗 沃格？
These tracks go around for miles, right, Vogel?
这条不是！
Not this one.
这条是死路？就是说我们会撞毁？
This track dead-ends, as in crash and burn?
我真的开始讨厌火车了！
I'm really starting to hate trains!
那是什么?
What was that?
欢迎来到地球！
Welcome to Earth!
沃格 不要！
Vogel, no!
她是好人！
She's one of the good guys!
阿尔茜 刹车失灵了！
Arcee, the brakes are shot!
有备用控制吗？
Is there any kind of emergency override?
没有 女士
N-No, ma'am!
不过前方有个扳道闸门
But there is a switch-track control up ahead.
只要拉动拉杆就行
If you can just adjust the pole rod...
看见你就明白了 可以转到另外一条轨道
You'll know it when you see it. It'll re-route us to another line.
她变成了一辆…摩托车？
Did she just turn into... a motorcycle?
啊哦
Uh-Oh.
那个是？
And that would be?
坏蛋
Trouble.
哇哦 看看是谁又能变形了
Well, well, look who got his treads back.
见鬼！
Scrap!
- 耶！\N- 好极了！\N- 太棒了！
- Yes!\N- Alright!\N- Sweet!
到妈妈这儿来
Come to mama.
电倒你
Shock and drop.
呼 前面畅通无阻
We're in the clear.
可我们还是得停下来
Still need a way to stop...
而不是一头撞上墙
beside slamming into a wall, I mean.
小心！
Watch out!
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
哥们！
Dude!
你怎么…没被撞到？
How did you not get mashed?
相位仪
Phase shifter.
可以让你穿过实体 或者让实体穿过你
Handy when you need to pass through solid objects. Or vice versa.
不 不！
No. No!!!
你们刮花了我的脸 我要你们好看！
You scratch my face, I scratch yours!
他都知道了 我们需要把他带上吗？
He knows. Do we have to take him with us?
上母舰？
To the mother ship?
我有个妙计
I think I have a work-around.
没错 战士
That's right, soldier!
扔了那块石头 快点回来！
Dump that rock and come on home!
我是福勒 神子？什么事？什么？
Fowler. Miko, what is it? What in the sam hill?
我正在处理危急事件 你却要我…
I'm in the middle of a crisis here, and you want me to...
…让他接电话
... put him on the line.
沃格先生 我是美国政府特工福勒
Mr. Vogel, this is special agent William Fowler of the United States government.
你特此被任命为星际关系部的 嗯…
You are hereby deputized as an honorary agent for the department of, um...
荣誉探员
interstellar relations.
谢谢您 长官！
Thank you, sir.
那么…我们保持联系？
So... you folks will be in touch?
当然
Abso-Freakin'-Lutely!
啊啊 不过我们得保持无线电静默
But until then
除非我们主动联系你
we need to maintain complete radio silence.
这是我的荣幸
It's been an honor.
点子不错 代理人
Good call, face.
哼 我了解大城市居民 他们在地下呆太久了
Eh, I understand big-city people... who spend way too much time below ground.
找到一个圣物 还剩三个
One relic down, three to go.
但愿其他人也有好消息
Let's hope the others are having similar results.
变成交通工具的机器人
Robots who turn into vehicles.
那么…
Hmm...